

Profile

Passionate and motivated software developer based in Milan with 2 years of professional experience developing with C# and Unity

Interested in all kinds of technologies, in particular everything regarding Shaders, Videogames, AR/VR/XR, and AI.

I think the best part of our job is to find a new problem to solve and nothing gratifies me the most than doing it.

I've spent 5 years working in the family business to pay for my studies, which's lead me to understand even more how much I love coding and in particular solving problems.

Employment History

Software Developer (C# - Unity), UpSurgeOn Srl, Milano

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

During my period working for UpSurgeOn as a Software developer on Unity I was able to focus on:

Unity, Online Stores Management, ARCore - ARKit, Shaders, UI, In-Depth Code optimization, Services (Savings, In-App Purchase, News), Database, Online Server API. Camera Behaviours

Professor of "Shader Basics", The Sign Comics & Arts Academy, Florence

OCTOBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

After my graduation, the academy offered me a 6 months job as a professor to teach new programmers my thesis subject.

It was an incredible experience teaching young game programmers about a subject that I love that much

Education

Game Programmer, Event Horizon School / TheSign Comics & Arts Academy, Florence

SEPTEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Final thesis: Shader (CG-HLSL)

3 Year course with focus on:

C#, C++, Unity, Teamwork, Working with artists and designers, working with other developers, multiplatform

Computer Engineering (Not completed), University of Pisa, Pisa

SEPTEMBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2014

I spent 2 years attending courses and exams.

I learned the principles of Programming, OOP, and attended courses of Algorithm and Data Structures, Operating System, Math and Physic

Courses

Details

Milan

Italy

+39 3935667302

giacomo_vanni@yahoo.it

NATIONALITY

Italian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

22/11/1993

Pisa

Links

Portfolio with complete projects track

Skills

C#

Unity

Shader (CG - HLSL)

C++

Version Control systems (Git)

OOP

HTML-CSS

Working with Designers/Artists

Languages

Italian

English

Hobbies

Videogames of every type, Card games, Tennis, Skiing

Shader Development using Unity, https://shaderdev.com/p/shader-development-using-unity-5

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2019

References

References available upon request

Extra-curricular activities

Receptionist, Dimora Antico Borgo, Terricciola, Terricciola

JANUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2019

To pay for my studies I've joined the family business and start handling social media and welcoming customers for our B&B/ Apartment service in Tuscany. where I learn in-depth knowledge on how to work and relate with customers

Internships

Unity Developer (Microsoft HoloLens), Balzo Srl, Florence

MAY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

After I've finished my first year at the academy, one of my professors offered me an internship at his company.

For four months I've worked hand to hand with senior developers using Microsoft HoloLens